"Someone must have been telling
lies about Josef K.
He knew he had done nothing wrong,
but one morning, he was arrested."
Thus begins "The Trial /审讯/,"
one of author Franz Kafka /ˈkæfkə/ 's
most well-known novels.
K, the protagonist /prəʊˈtæɡənɪst 主演/,
is arrested out of nowhere
and made to go through
a bewildering / bɪˈwɪldə 使迷惑，使不知所措/ process
where neither the cause of his arrest,
nor the nature
of the judicial /dʒuːˈdɪʃəl 公正的；司法的，法庭的/ proceedings
are made clear to him.
This sort of scenario /sɪˈnɑːrɪˌəʊ 情节；剧本；方案/ is considered
so characteristic of Kafka's work
that scholars came up
with a new word for it.
Kafkaesque /ˌkæfkəˈesk 卡夫卡风格/ has entered the vernacular /vəˈnækjʊlə 本地风格   方言/
to describe unnecessarily complicated /ˈkɒmplɪˌkeɪtɪd 复杂的/
and frustrating /frʌˈstreɪt 挫败/ experiences,
like being forced to navigate labyrinths /ˈlæbərɪnθ 迷宫；错综复杂的事物/
of bureaucracy /bjʊəˈrɒkrəsɪ 官僚主义/.
But does standing in a long line
to fill out confusing paperwork
really capture the richness
of Kafka's vision?
Beyond the word's casual /ˈkæʒjʊəl 偶然的 非正式的/ use,
what makes something Kafkaesque?
Franz Kafka's stories do indeed deal
with many mundane /ˈmʌndeɪn 平凡的，单调的/ and absurd /əbˈsɜːd 荒谬的，可笑的/ aspects
of modern bureaucracy /bjʊəˈrɒkrəsɪ/,
drawn in part from his experience
of working as an insurance clerk
in early 20th century Prague /prɑːɡ/.
Many of his protagonists /prəʊˈtæɡənɪst 主演/
are office workers
compelled /kəmˈpɛl 强迫/ to struggle through
a web of obstacles /ˈɒbstəkəl n 障碍（物），干扰/
in order to achieve their goals,
and often the whole ordeal /ɔːˈdiːl 折磨，严酷的考验/ turns out
to be so disorienting /dɪsˈɔːrɪent 使迷失方向/ and illogical / ɪˈlɒdʒɪkəl 不合逻辑的/
that success becomes pointless /ˈpɔɪntlɪs 不得要领的/
in the first place.
For example, in the short story,
"Poseidon /pɔ'saidn/,"
the Ancient Greek god is an executive
so swamped /swɒmp 使沉没/ with paperwork
that he's never had time to explore
his underwater domain.
The joke here is that not even
a god can handle the amount of paperwork
demanded by the modern workplace.
But the reason why is telling.
He's unwilling to delegate /ˈdɛlɪˌɡeɪt/ any of the work
because he deems /diːm 认为 主张/ everyone else
unworthy of the task.
Kafka's Poseidon is a prisoner
of his own ego /ˈiːɡəʊ 自我；自负；完全人/.
This simple story contains
all of the elements
that make for a truly Kafkaesque scenario /sɪˈnɑːrɪˌəʊ 情节/.
It's not the absurdity  /əbˈsɜːdɪtɪ 荒谬/
of bureaucracy /bjʊəˈrɒkrəsɪ/ alone,
but the irony of the character's
circular /ˈsɜːkjʊlə/ reasoning in reaction to it
that is emblematic /embliˈmætik 标志的，象征性的/ of Kafka's writing.
His tragicomic /trædʒi'kɔmik 悲喜剧/ stories act as a form of
mythology /mɪˈθɒlədʒɪ 神话/  for the modern industrial /ɪnˈdʌstrɪəl/ age,
employing dream logic to explore
the relationships
between systems of arbitrary /ˈɑːbɪtrərɪ 任意的，武断的；专制的 / power
and the individuals caught up in them.
Take, for example, Kafka's
most famous story, "Metamorphosis /ˌmɛtəˈmɔːfəsɪs 变形/."
When Gregor Samsa awaken's one morning
to find himself transformed
into a giant insect,
his greatest worry
is that he gets to work on time.
Of course, this proves impossible.
It was not only the authoritarian /ɔːˌθɒrɪˈteərɪən 独裁主义者/ realm /rɛlm 王国 领域/
of the workplace that inspired Kafka.
Some of his protagonists /prəʊˈtæɡənɪst/' struggles
come from within.
The short story, "A Hunger Artist,"
describes a circus /ˈsɜːkəs 马戏团；马戏表演 / performer whose act
consists of extended fasts.
He's upset that the circus master
limits these to 40 days,
believing this prevents him from achieving
greatness in his art.
But when his act loses popularity /ˌpɒpjʊˈlærɪtɪ/,
he is left free
to starve himself to death.
The twist comes when he lays dying
in anonymity /ˌænɒˈnɪmɪtɪ  匿名/,
regretfully admitting that his art
has always been a fraud.
He fasted not through strength of will,
but simply because he never found
a food he liked.
Even in "The Trial,"
which seems to focus
directly on bureaucracy,
the vague /veɪɡ 模糊不清的/ laws and bewildering /bɪˈwɪldə 迷惑/ procedures
point to something far more sinister /ˈsɪnɪstə 危险的 阴险的/:
the terrible momentum /məʊˈmɛntəm 动量/ of the legal system
proves unstoppable,
even by supposedly powerful officials.
This is a system
that doesn't serve justice,
but whose sole function
is to perpetuate /pəˈpetʃʊˌeɪt 使永存/ itself.
What political theorist Hannah Arendt,
writing years after Kafka's death,
would call "tyranny /ˈtɪrənɪ 暴政；暴虐/ without a tyrant /taɪrənt  暴君/."
Yet accompanying
the bleakness /ˈbliːknɪs 荒芜；苍凉/ of Kafka's stories,
there's a great deal of humor
rooted in the nonsensical /nɒnˈsensɪkəl 荒唐的/ logic
of the situations described.
So on the one hand, it's easy to recognize
the Kafkaesque in today's world.
We rely on increasingly convoluted /ˈkɒnvəˌluːt 卷曲的 回旋/ systems
of administration
that have real consequences on
every aspect of our lives.
And we find our every word judged
by people we can't see
according to rules we don't know.
On the other hand, by fine-tuning /tun 曲调/
our attention to the absurd /əbˈsɜːd 荒诞/,
Kafka also reflects our shortcomings /ˈʃɔːtˌkʌmɪŋ 缺点，短处/
back at ourselves.
In doing so, he reminds us that the world
we live in is one we create,
and have the power
to change for the better.